The will was sent back to the capital
Завещание было доставлено в столицу
Xie Xuan was ordered to assist in governance
Се Сюань был назначен регентом
Crown Prince Sikong Sheng successfully ascended the throne
наследный принц Сыкун Шэн без помех взошёл на трон
Posthumously titled you as Emperor Xuancheng
присвоил ему посмертный титул император Сюаньчэн
And changed the era name to Taian the following year
На следующий год провозгласил новую эпоху Тайань
After Sikong Sheng ascended the throne
После восшествия Сыкун Шэна на престол
Although nominally the ruler of all under heaven
хотя формально он стал правителем всей Поднебесной
The army still had many remnants of Sikong Xu's faction
в армии всё ещё оставались сторонники Сыкун Сюя
Threatening the state's stability
угрожая стабильности государства
Grand General Zhu Yuanzhi, in the name of intimidating border tribes
Генерал Чжу Юаньчжи под предлогом сдерживания кочевых племён
Stationed troops at the Yan Bei border
разместил войска у границ Яньбея
Regarding this
В ответ на это
Sikong Sheng adopted a strategy of divide and conquer
Сыкун Шэн применил стратегию разделения
On one hand
с одной стороны
Forgiving the past
прошлое не преследовалось
And giving rewards to all
и всех наградил
On the other hand
с другой стороны
For those who repeatedly disobeyed court orders
тех кто не подчинялся приказам двора
Carrying out targeted punishment
подвергал точечным наказаниям
Although this was effective
Хотя эта мера имела эффект
Many of the Prince of Yan's former subordinates, though appearing to submit
многие старые сторонники князя Янь хоть и подчинились внешне
Still harbored resentment in their hearts
в душе всё ещё затаили обиду
And after Zhu Yuanzhi was summoned to the capital
И после того как Чжу Юаньчжи был вызван в столицу
And given a nominal position
и назначен на номинальную должность
Became even more closely connected
они стали общаться ещё теснее
The fourth year of Taian
В четвёртый год Тайаня
Sikong Sheng, in the name of returning to the old capital
Сыкун Шэн под предлогом возвращения в старую столицу
Wished to move the capital to Yong'an
хотел перенести столицу в Юнъань
Moving the political center north
переместив политический центр на север
Met with fierce opposition from Zhu Yuanzhi
что встретило сопротивление Чжу Юаньчжи в союзе со старой аристократией
United with old friends, noble families, and scholar clans
яростное сопротивление
Finally forced to abandon the plan
в итоге пришлось оставить эту затею